The mouse is sniffing around for a meal.
He'll eat almost anything, but prefers
seeds, nuts and vegetation.
Like all mice, he feels safer near
vertical surfaces, rocks, grass and trees.
It maximises his escape options.
This little guy is an excellent all-round
athlete.
He can run, climb, jump and swim.
A juicy crop of lush green seedlings.
The food has attracted a range of small
hungry mammals, and the small mammals have
attracted something else.
A barn owl.
The mouse is unaware of her presence.
Owls have acute hearing and can move in
absolute silence.
But the mouse is well camouflaged.
The owl is on the prowl.
Her soft wings carry her through the
forest as she scans the undergrowth.
The mouse is hard to spot, but not
impossible.
His race is over.
This tiger snake has highly sensitive
smell.
The darkness is not a problem when you're
relying on smell.
The mouse can smell something.
Mice are born knowing which smells signal
danger.
Now the mouse has no choice but to keep
still, wait and hope he hasn't been
noticed.
But the snake is onto him.
The mouse has a very unwelcome guest.
He's trapped.
It's game over for the mouse.